

CONTACT

0790 852 3013

nickkagamemusic@gmail.com

github.com/nickkagame

Linkedin

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript
React, React Native, HTML/CSS
Express, SQL, Firebase,
NoSQL, Node.js
Testing: Jest, Supertest

EDUCATION

MA Humanitarianism & Conflict Response
University of Manchester
2012

BA Politics and Philosophy
2.1
University of Manchester
2007-2010

ACHIEVEMENTS

The Weston Charity Award
The Garfield Weston
Foundation
2020

The Guardian Charity Award
The Guardian
2016

Nick K. Jones

Full-Stack Software Developer

SUMMARY

Through my career change to Software Development, I have added experience working in the whole Javascript ecosystem, to extensive leadership, managerial, business-planning and collaborative skills gained through eight years managing a charity. Coding has reinvigorated my love of learning and problem solving, and provides rare states of focused creative flow. This fuels my passionate dedication to further development, reflected in current personal projects focused on building skills in AWS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

Mancro | Remote | 2023

- Worked in an agile team of 5 developers, using standard Git Workflow practices to develop a mobile application for Android and iOS
- Facilitated team planning meetings regarding technical decisions and led on daily whiteboarding and ticket delegation
- Worked with unfamiliar tech to spike potential blockers before development, and added new elements to our tech-stack to achieve desired results
- Working in a mixed ability team, clear empathetic and friendly communication, delegation and meeting facilitation skills were key to building a friendly and supportive environment where all felt valued, which was reflected in our team retrospective

Project Link: github.com/nickkagame/Pets-reunited

Technologies: React Native, Firebase, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Expo, CSS

Junior Full-Stack Developer

Northcoders | Manchester/Remote | 2022 - 2023

- A intensive programme of software development where I collaborated with fellow junior full stack developers on numerous front-end and back-end projects
- Built applications, websites and APIs from scratch, and solidified skills in the fundamentals of Javascript, and front-end, back-end and testing frameworks
- Demonstrated strong, problem solving skills relying on self-tuition and documentation for several frameworks to independently find solutions
- Quickly grasped a wide range of programming concepts, demonstrated through timely completion of time-limited solo front end and back projects, and going beyond the brief to develop additional features associated with UI/UX
- Excelled working in teams, and pairs, and supported colleagues with technical problems, and demonstrated notable skills in Test Driven Development in my solo work

Project Links: github.com/nickkagame/NK-NEWS github.com/nickkagame/nk-nc-news main--cosmic-trifle-ac55a6.netlifv.app

Technologies: React, Express, postgreSQL, NoSQL, Node.js, Jest, Supertest, HTML, CSS

LANGUAGES

English | Native
Spanish | Intermediate

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Northcoders 2022

CHARITY LEADERSHIP Pilot Light 2021 - 2022

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Creative Producer / Programme & Finance Manager

Music Action International | 2013 – 2022

- Responsible for running an arts charity supporting refugee survivors of war, torture and persecution, through music
- Managed several projects in the North-West, South-East England and beyond

 included negotiating fees and partnership agreements, monitoring and
 evaluation, delivery team recruitment, payments, and scheduling the work of
 over 45 freelance project delivery staff and volunteers annually
- Responsible for developing and executing overall fundraising and growth strategies, bookkeeping and financial forecasting. Resulted in annual turnover more than quadrupling in three years, followed by new income in excess of £1.5million, and repeated core funding via the Arts Council's National Portfolio
- Developed and maintained close partnerships with a hugely diverse range of arts and refugee support organisations, artists, and high-profile, community, and multi-purpose venues, to facilitate ambitious and complex projects, events and performances

Online Content Management and Marketing Assistant

Whosampled.com | 2011-2012

- Part of a small team focused on the growth of a music website visited by over 1 million users monthly
- Devised, budgeting and executed a targeted online advertising campaign to boost use of the company's mobile app
- Responsible for meticulously verifying the accuracy of thousands of user-generated data entries, maintaining the quality of a large online database,
- Collaboratively determined the best course f or the website's redesign

FURTHER INFORMATION

Music: As a music producer and professional DJ, I curate a series of underground electronic music events in temporary venues in Manchester and beyond. I perform at events and festivals in the UK and Europe, while also pursuing jazz bass and classical piano, and producing original music (electronic).

Voluntary work: Work as a volunteer at refugee drop-ins, football and music sessions for refugee survivors of torture and support Partisan Collective (DIY community-led events, and cultural projects) with fundraising, events and financial management.